Guide to the Nina Rosenblum Papers MSS.558
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series XIII. Unintended Consequences, 1998-2008; 11.69 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 5 record cartons, 2 small flat boxes, 5 cassette boxes, and 1 folder in a shared oversized box; 4 DAT; 9 Betacam_SP; 2 Hi8; 190 MiniDV; 1 VHS-C; 2 audiocassette; 2.71 Gigabytes in 22 computer files
  - Subseries XIII.C. Production Materials, 2000-2010; 9.29 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 5 record cartons, 1 small flat box, and 4 cassette boxes; 9 Betacam_SP; 4 DAT; 141 MiniDV; 2 Hi8; 1 VHS-C; 2.69 Gigabytes in 4 computer files
    This subseries consists of materials used in the production of the film. Most of the materials are video recordings, but there are some audio recordings and correspondence.
    - Adam Clayton Powell, June 14, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0868)
    - Albany March
      - #1, January 3, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0831)
      - #2, January 3, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0873)
      - #3, January 3, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0801)
      - #3, January 3, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0870)
      - #4, January 3, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0872)
    - Alby Talking, undated (Box 44, Minidv 558.0707)
    - Black History Trip, undated (Box 35, Minidv 558.0718)
    - Brooklyn, May 9, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0808)
    - Brooklyn DA, May 9, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0846)
    - Budget Talk on Bus, undated (Box 35, Minidv 558.0682)
    - Calvin Baker
      - Hearing, May 3, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0861)
      - Rikers Island #1, May 15, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0800)
      - Rikers Island #1 -- Master, May 15, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0837)
      - Rikers Island #2 -- Bail, May 15, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0812)
      - Rikers Island #2 -- Bail, May 16, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0802)
    - Cantor Film Center -- New York University, April 30, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0836)
    - Carl and Rock Speak to Kids, undated (Box 44, Minidv 558.0700)
    - Charlie the Tuna, undated (Box 35, Minidv 558.0739)
    - Conviction Day, April 20, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0805)
    - Conviction Day and Andre L., April 20, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0710)
    - Correspondence, 2001-2003 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Court TV, undated (Box 35, Minidv 558.0740)
    - CUNY Grad #2, May 31, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0830)
    - Day at Park -- Fishing and Baseball, undated (Box 35, Minidv 558.0744)
    - Donna and Shameka
      - Donna #2, February 16, 2002 (Box 35, Minidv 558.0737)
      - Donna and Shameka, January 30, 2002 (Box 35, Minidv 558.0722)
      - Donna and Shameka, February 15, 2002 (Box 35, Minidv 558.0721)
      - Donna and Shameka #3, February 6, 2002 (Box 35, Minidv 558.0728)
      - Donna and Shameka, undated (Box 35, Minidv 558.0720)
      - Donna/St. Johns/T-Spoon, January 30, 2002 (Box 35, Minidv 558.0734)
      - Donna/St. Johns/T-Spoon, January 30, 2002 (Box 35, Minidv 558.0723)
      - Shameka, undated (Box 35, Minidv 558.0725)
      - Shameka Basketball Game, undated (Box 35, Minidv 558.0719)
      - Shameka Game 1, January 23, 2002 (Box 35, Minidv 558.0731)
      - Shameka Game 1, February 6, 2002 (Box 35, Minidv 558.0726)
      - Shameka Game 1/Andre #1, January 23, 2002 (Box 35, Minidv 558.0727)
      - Shameka Game 2, January 30, 2002 (Box 35, Minidv 558.0745)
      - Shameka Game 2, January 30, 2002 (Box 35, Minidv 558.0730)
      - Shameka Game 2, January 30, 2002 (Box 35, Minidv 558.0683)
      - Shameka Game #2/Donna, February 6, 2002 (Box 35, Minidv 558.0732)
    - Echoing Green
      - Dinner, July 19, 2002 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0827)
      - Dinner -- Bill P., July 21, 2002 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0857)
      - Echoing Seed #2 -- Goes to Court, July 20, 2002 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0828)
      - "Seed, Intro, Acct", July 20, 2002 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0855)
    - Electronic Recordings and Photographs, 2004-2010; FA_MSS_558_ER_59
    - Estevez Family, Tuna at College, and Milbank, 2003 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0697)
    - Ethical Culture
      - #1, March 1, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0832)
      - #2, March 1, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0869)
      - Ethical Culture, undated (Box 37, Dat 558.0703)
      - Judge Marks Statement, February 29, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0833)
    - Final Film Versions
      - 8 Minute Version -- Mediarights.org, March 14, 2002 (Box 32, Betacam sp 558.0456)
      - 9 Minute Final Version -- Master, March 27, 2002 (Box 30, Betacam sp 558.0537)
      - 15 and 9 Minute Versions -- Master, undated (Box 32, Betacam sp 558.0452)
      - 15 Minute Version, May 21, 2001 (Box 25, Betacam sp 558.0109)
      - 15 Minute Version, March 14, 2002 (Box 31, Betacam sp 558.0618)
      - 15 Minute Final Version, May 2, 2002 (Box 30, Betacam sp 558.0536)
    - Grandma and Carmen Papote, November 29, 2000 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0874)
    - Grandma Funeral, undated (Box 35, Minidv 558.0733)
    - Home Videos
      - Bianel, Andy, Christian, Leni, undated (Box 35, Minidv 558.0749)
      - Bianel and Christian's Last Tape, undated (Box 35, Minidv 558.0750)
      - Luis, Shawn, Josh, Kimberly, July 22, 2003 (Box 35, Minidv 558.0738)
    - Jan Warren
      - #1, January 26, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0852)
      - #2, January 26, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0853)
    - John Dunne
      - #1, February 17, 200 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0864)
      - Dunne and Satoko, February 16, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0825)
      - Dunne and Terrence, February 14, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0826)
      - R. Law Roundtable, January 11, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0863)
    - Justice Works
      - Demo, May 11, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0844)
      - Demo, May 11, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0847)
      - Dinner, May 18, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0856)
      - Dinner, May 18, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0858)
      - Justice Works, undated (Box 44, Minidv 558.0859)
    - Lab School, March 26, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0809)
    - Len Levinson
      - After Baker Interview, May 15, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0814)
      - Baker Case #1, April 26, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0813)
    - Media That Matters #1 Party and Film Opening, June 14, 2002 (Box 40, Minidv 558.0237)
    - The Michigan Project -- Tracy Neal Trial
      - Tape #1 -- Master, March 22, 2000 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0816)
      - Tape #2 -- Master -- Police, Detroit-Greektown, Fist/Statue, March 22, 2000 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0817)
      - Tape #3 -- Master, March 22, 2000 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0818)
      - Tape #4 -- Master, March 22, 2000 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0819)
      - Tape #5 -- Master, March 22, 2000 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0820)
    - "The Mooche and Jitterbug Waltz", undated (Box 37, Dat 558.0702)
    - Nina's Casa by Fanny, June 19, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0854)
    - "NRP422 Ark" -- Summer, 2003 (Box 35, Minidv 558.0743)
    - Queens Courthouse
      - #1, February 28, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0842)
      - #2, February 28, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0843)
    - Park -- Baseball, July 24, 2003 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0681)
    - People with Flag -- World Trade Center, NYC, undated (Box 44, Minidv 558.0695)
    - Project Greenhouse, April 20, 2001 (Box 35, Minidv 558.0729)
    - Protest in Front of Pataki's Office, May 8, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0829)
    - Real Estate -- Al Talks to Kids, undated (Box 35, Minidv 558.0724)
    - Rob and Taylor
      - Bronx Zoo and Takeover, undated (Box 35, Minidv 558.0741)
      - Last Tape, undated (Box 44, Minidv 558.0696)
    - Rockefeller Drug Program
      - Rockefeller Drug Program #1, March 1, 2001 (Box 37, Dat 558.0834)
      - Rockefeller Drug Program #2, March 1, 2001 (Box 37, Dat 558.0835)
      - Drop the Rock Day -- Tape 1, March 27, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0849)
      - Drop the Rock Day -- Tape 2, March 27, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0850)
      - Drop the Rock Day -- Tape 3, March 27, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0851)
      - Drop the Rock -- R1, November 15, 2003 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0841)
      - Void -- Drop the Rock, November 15, 2003 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0840)
      - Drop the Rock, June 15, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0845)
    - Safespace -- Webster Hall, May 7, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0848)
    - Shawn and JJ -- Cooking Show/Family Talk/Bronx Zoo, undated (Box 44, Minidv 558.0699)
    - Shawn's Cooking Show/Shooting at Maysles, undated (Box 35, Minidv 558.0736)
    - Steve and Rock -- Powerhouse Studio/Schomburg Center/Dorney Park/Fishing in Central Park, 2003 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0698)
    - Still 2 of Andre's Photo, undated (Box 44, Minidv 558.0867)
    - Susan -- Tape 2, April 20, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0810)
    - T. Aviles
      - Fanny, June 20, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0871)
      - Isidro Aviles Funeral, undated (Box 32, Betacam sp 558.0457)
      - "Last Fanny's", undated (Box 44, Minidv 558.0862)
      - Mother's Day -- Aviles #1, May 13, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0860)
      - Mother's Day -- Aviles #2, May 13, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0865)
      - Project Andre, undated (Box 43, Minidv 558.0815)
      - Project Fennie, undated (Box 43, Minidv 558.0838)
      - Teresa Aviles and Andre, June 20, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0866)
    - "Take Over"
      - #2, undated (Box 35, Minidv 558.0748)
      - #3, undated (Box 35, Minidv 558.0746)
      - Extras, undated (Box 35, Minidv 558.0747)
      - Take Over and City College, undated (Box 44, Minidv 558.0716)
    - Testimony -- NYC Demo, May 8, 2008 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0839)
    - Terrence Stevens
      - Birthday, September 16, 2003 (Box 35, Minidv 558.0735)
      - Comes Home, January 31, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0685)
      - Clemency, January 31, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0686)
      - Clemency, January 31, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0687)
      - Clemency, January 31, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0705)
      - Dr. Lange -- Tape 1, May 21, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0712)
      - Dr. Lange -- Tape 2, May 21, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0713)
      - Getting Bed, undated (Box 44, Minidv 558.0692)
      - Getting Bed -- 1 of 2, April 6, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0806)
      - Getting Bed -- 2 of 2 -- Master, April 6, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0689)
      - Going into "Famm Whitehouse", July 21, 2002 (Box 35, Minidv 558.0742)
      - Harlem -- Outreach, June 14, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0690)
      - In the Bath, March 25, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0708)
      - In the Bath and Andre, March 25, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0694)
      - Master, May 21, 2001 (Box 24, Betacam sp 558.0572)
      - On Dinkins Radio, August 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0811)
      - Physical Therapy, April 20, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0701)
      - Pool Therapy, July 31, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0704)
      - Pool Therapy and Lawsuit, July 31, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0693)
      - Rally, February 28, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0688)
      - St. Francis Church, April 19, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0711)
      - Terrence, April 20, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0684)
      - Terrence and Andre #5, February 20, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0691)
      - Terrence and Andre #6 -- No Audio at Beginning, February 19, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0714)
      - Terrence and Andre -- Computer, March 14, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0807)
      - Terrence Sick/Terrence and Sister/Andre Lambertson, March 15, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0706)
      - Update, February 7, 2001 (Box 44, Minidv 558.0709)
      - Update #2, February 7, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0821)
      - To Get Van #1, July 20, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0804)
      - To Get Van, July 20, 2001 (Box 35, Minidv 558.0764)
      - World Gym, BBC, Nina, August 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0803)
    - Treatment and Weekly Reports, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Unintended Consequences, undated (Box 32, Betacam sp 558.0455)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 35, Hi8 558.0752)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 35, Hi8 558.0753)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 44, Vhs-c 558.0754)
    - Vassar
      - 1 of 2, March 31, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0822)
      - 2 of 2, March 31, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0823)
      - Fuzzy Broccoli Radio, July 15, 2001 (Box 43, Minidv 558.0824)
  - Subseries XIII.D. Research Materials, 1998-2004; 1.77 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box and 1 large flat box; 11 kilobytes in 2 computer files
    This subseries contains research materials used in the making of the film, such as news articles and an informational poster.
    - Articles and Letters, 1998-2000 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Electronic Records -- Articles, 2004; FA_MSS_558_ER_60
    - Poster, undated (Box Shared Fales 116, Folder 6)
- Series XIV. Code Yellow: Hospital at Ground Zero, 2001-2014; 2.02 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 2 small flat boxes, 1 cassette box, and 1 medium flat box; 1 Hi8; 57 MiniDV; 18.5 Gigabytes in 38 computer files
  This series encompasses materials related to Code Yellow: Hospital at Ground Zero, a feature documentary produced in association with New York University Downtown Hospital. Released in 2002, it chronicles the medical response of the hospital closest to Ground Zero on September 11, 2001. Materials related to the production, marketing, and screening of the film include a scrapbook, press, posters, photographs, and film elements (such as interviews, raw footage, and credits) on various media.
  Arranged alphabetically into two subseries and alphanumerically within each one.
  - Subseries XIV.A. Marketing Materials and Screenings, 2002-2014; .69 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box and 1 medium flat box; 14.6 Megabytes in 3 computer files
    - DVD Cover and Poster, 2005-2010; FA_MSS_558_ER_62
    - Screening and Festival Programs, Flyers, and Schedules, 2002-2014 (Box 13, Folder 20, Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Synopsis, Postcard, and Letterhead, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Subseries XIV.B. Production Materials, 2001-2012; 1.77 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 2 small flat boxes, and 1 cassette box; 1 Hi8; 57 MiniDV; 18.4 Gigabytes in 35 computer files
    This subseries consists of materials related to the making of the film; most of the materials are video recordings, but there are also photographs, a production book, and an analog copy of the credits.
    - 9/11 Memorial Lights, April 1, 2002 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0756)
    - B Roll -- No Dubs, October 26, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0793)
    - Brian Dennehy, July 17, 2002 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0767)
    - Code Yellow: Hospital at Ground Zero, undated (Box 39, Minidv 558.0799)
    - Correspondence
      - Electronic Record, 2009; FA_MSS_558_ER_61
      - Letters and Email Printouts, 2001-2009 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Darren
      - 137 W. 22 St., September 11, 2001 (Box 36, Minidv 558.0382)
      - #2, September 11, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0763)
    - Debbie
      - Release, December 20, 2002 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0758)
      - Reunion, December 18, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0757)
    - Electronic Recordings, 2004-2012; FA_MSS_558_ER_63
    - Ground Zero -- Christmas Eve, December 24, 2002 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0771)
    - Joshua Clan -- Audio Only, October 4, 2002 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0765)
    - Lower Thirds and Credits, 2001-2002 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Mark Bernard
      - #1, April 15, 2002 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0762)
      - #2, April 15, 2002 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0769)
      - #3, April 16, 2002 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0770)
      - #4, undated (Box 39, Minidv 558.0760)
    - Photographs, circa 2001-2002; FA_MSS_558_ER_64
    - Production Book, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - NYU Downtown Hospital
      - #1, September 26, 2001 (Box 36, Minidv 558.0450)
      - #1, October 3, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0788)
      - #1, October 8, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0789)
      - #2, September 25, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0796)
      - #2, September 26, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0798)
      - #2, October 8, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0790)
      - #2, December 18, 2002 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0778)
      - #3 -- Cafeteria, Cleaning, Interviews, September 26, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0797)
      - #3, October 3, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0780)
      - #3, October 8, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0791)
      - #4, September 18, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0781)
      - #4, September 26, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0795)
      - #5, September 18, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0782)
      - WTC Disaster #1, September 18, 2001 (Box 36, Minidv 558.0442)
      - WTC Disaster #2, September 18, 2001 (Box 36, Minidv 558.0443)
      - WTC Disaster #3, September 18, 2001 (Box 36, Minidv 558.0444)
      - WTC Disaster JS #3, September 24, 2001 (Box 36, Minidv 558.0447)
      - WTC JS #6, September 20, 2001 (Box 36, Minidv 558.0445)
      - WTC JS #7, September 20, 2001 (Box 36, Minidv 558.0446)
      - Aubrey Ginsburg, November 16, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0785)
      - Dr. Logan and Dr. Geoffrey Weber-Young, October 29, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0766)
      - Paul Yellin, November 30, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0787)
      - Richard Ruth and John Mark, December 17, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0777)
      - Rudolph, December 17, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0775)
      - Wanda, Tony, Grace, Ginsburg, November 16, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0786)
      - Tony and Nancy Bernard in Hospital, November 8, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0774)
      - Tony Looks out Windows/Security Person/Exteriors, October 3, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0768)
      - Tony Wrap-Up, December 19, 2002 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0761)
    - NYU Engineer -- Roof, November 1, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0783)
    - NYU Hospital Photo Show -- Grand Central, January 8, 2002 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0776)
    - NYU Trade Dept. #2, November 1, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0784)
    - NYU Uptown Hospital -- WTC Disaster
      - #1, September 24, 2001 (Box 36, Minidv 558.0449)
      - #2, September 24, 2001 (Box 36, Minidv 558.0448)
    - Podiatrist Interview -- Dr. Bill Cole, November 13, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0773)
    - Stuart Sternberg/Marilyn, November 30, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0772)
    - Tony and Bill
      - #1, April 28, 2002 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0759)
      - #1, April 2002 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0755)
    - Tony into Towers/Cousins/Beekman 100, October 29, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0794)
    - World Trade Center
      - 1 -- St. Vincent's Hospital/Missing Posters/Fire Department, October 25, 2001 (Box 40, Minidv 558.0342)
      - 1 and 2 -- Bombing, September 11, 2001 (Box 40, Minidv 558.0341)
      - 2 -- Flute Player, Barricades, Digital Armageddon, October 25, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0779)
      - 3 -- Interview with Policeman, October 25, 2001 (Box 39, Minidv 558.0792)
      - Raw Footage and Helicopter Footage, October 2001 (Box 40, Minidv 558.0238)
      - World Trade Center, undated (Box 40, Hi8 558.0235)
- Series XV. An Empty Place at the Table, 1991-2002; 5.65 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes and 4 record cartons; 30 VHS
  This series contains materials related to a short film, An Empty Place at the Table, directed by Rosenblum that accompanied an exhibit of the same name in Scranton, Pennslyvania in 2002. The exhibition and film focus on domestic violence and related materials include research material (such as an exhibition manual and news clippings), a scrapbook, and film elements (such as interviews, exhibition shots, and exterior shots) on various media.
  Content Warning: Materials include personal accounts of personal trauma and domestic abuse.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic and alphanumerically within the first one.
  - Production Materials
    - #12 New Setting at Museum, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0631)
    - #17 Take Back the Night -- Candle Light Vigil at County Court House, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0625)
    - #18 My Mother's Table -- Guy Tattoo Waiter 2nd, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0638)
    - #22 Jackie Marshalek, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0621)
    - #24 Justice Center -- Jackie, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0620)
    - #26 O'Malley, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0639)
    - #28 Judge Harhut, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0634)
    - #31 Donna's Interview -- Walkthrough with Reporter, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0628)
    - Alice
      - #11 Alice 2, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0632)
      - #29 Alice 1, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0641)
    - Alice and Josh
      - #2 -- Restaurant, May 18, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0629)
      - Alice and Josh, May 18, 2002 (Box 25, Vhs 558.0255)
      - Timecode -- Ankle Bracelet, May 18, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0611)
    - EPT Exhibit Shots -- 2nd Unit
      - #14, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0637)
      - #14, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0624)
      - #15, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0640)
      - #15, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0623)
    - HAGZ -- Lastest Cut, April 17, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0619)
    - Outlines and Notes, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Peg and Ellen
      - #33 Peg Drives and Peg's Porch, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0635)
      - #33 Peg Drives and Peg's Porch, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0636)
    - Phyllis Mashie
      - #1, May 19, 2002 (Box 27, Vhs 558.0257)
      - #5, May 19, 2002 (Box 60, Vhs 558.0205)
    - Police Ride Only
      - #30, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0626)
      - #30, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0627)
    - Scranton
      - #1 Scranton Shots, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0622)
      - #13 Scranton Shots, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0630)
      - #26 Scranton Women's Rec Board, 2002 (Box 31, Vhs 558.0633)
    - Women's Resource Center
      - #20 Table Exhibit -- Train, Interviews, 2002 (Box 27, Vhs 558.0258)
      - #27 The Grave Yard, 2002 (Box 60, Vhs 558.0210)
      - Scranton Stores -- Women in Kitchen -- Yellow #19, 2002 (Box 32, Vhs 558.0259)
  - Research Material -- Art Exhibit Manual and Clippings, 1991-2000 (Box 13, Folder 21)
- Series XVI. Zahira's Peace, 2004-2014; 4.48 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 3 record cartons, and 1 cassette box; 11 Betacam_SP; 11 Digital_Betacam; 1 MiniDV; 5 VHS; 1.26 Gigabytes in 55 computer files
  This series encompasses materials related to Zahira's Peace, a feature documentary that tells the story of Zahira, a young woman gravely injured on March 11, 2004, in the Atocha train station bombing in Madrid, Spain. Also released in 2004, materials related to the production, marketing, and screening of the film include posters, press, a scrapbook, photographs, and film elements (such as subtitled versions, English versions, Spanish versions, and a trailer) on various media.
  - Subseries XVI.A. Administrative Materials, 2004-2006; .44 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box; 126 kilobytes in 5 computer files
    This subseries includes office files such as correspondence and a budget.
    - Budget, 2004; FA_MSS_558_ER_72
    - Correspondence, 2005-2006
      - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_558_ER_73
      - Letters and Email Printouts (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Subseries XVI.B. Marketing Materials, 2004-2014; .44 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box; 16.6 Megabytes in 8 computer files
    This subseries contains materials related to the marketing of the film such as posters, synopses in English and Spanish, and a postcard.
    - Spanish and English Posters and DVD Cover, 2004-2014; FA_MSS_558_ER_74
    - Synopses in English and Spanish, Press Release, and Postcard, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Subseries XVI.C. Press and Awards, 2004-2006; 1.52 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box and 1 record carton; 4 Betacam_SP; 44 kilobytes in 2 computer files
    This subseries includes publicity materials related to the film and materials on the awards received by the film. Materials consist of an award announcement, electronic press kits, reviews, and a publicity scrapbook.
    - Award
      - Announcement, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - Electronic Records, 2005-2006; FA_MSS_558_ER_71
    - Electronic Press Kits (EPKs)
      - English #1, undated (Box 23, Betacam sp 558.0306)
      - English #2, undated (Box 23, Betacam sp 558.0307)
      - Spanish #1, undated (Box 23, Betacam sp 558.0303)
      - Spanish #2, March 8, 2005 (Box 23, Betacam sp 558.0305)
    - Press Releases, Articles, and Reviews, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Scrapbook, 2004-2006 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Subseries XVI.D. Production Materials, 4.48 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 3 record cartons, and 1 cassette box; 7 Betacam_SP; 11 Digital_Betacam; 1 MiniDV; 5 VHS; 1.24 Gigabytes in 37 computer files